Mahendra Duwal Shrestha

57 Village Cir Apt 244 ● Rochester Hills, MI 48307 ● (865) 441-7363 ● mduwalsh@vols.utk.edu

• <u>duwal.mahendra@gmail.com</u>

SUMMARY

A software engineer with 2.7 years of professional industry experience in C#, Asp.Net MVC, Java, Grails. Proven abilities in analysis, test driven development and multi-tiered web application development. 2.9 years of research experience in developing computational simulation programs involving cluster computations in C/C++.

EDUCATION

MS in Computer Science, The University of Tennessee, Knoxville, GPA: 3.88

2014-2017

Major courses taken: Computer Systems Organization, Software Systems, Algorithms, Introduction to Pattern Recognition, Databases and Scripting Languages, Applied

Cryptography, Distributed System Algorithms

Thesis: Efficient Simulation Of A Simple Evolutionary System

BE in Electronics and Communication Engineering, Pulchowk Engineering

2007-2011

Campus, Tribhuvan University, Nepal, GPA: 3.8

SKILLS SUMMARY

Programming Language: C#, C, C++, Java, Javascript

Technologies: ASP.Net, ASP.Net MVC, HTML5, Grails, Ajax, Jquery, JSON,

Web services, WCF services, REST, SOAP, Hibernate,

Entity Framework, LINQ, Spring MVC

Version Control: git, TFS, subversionDatabases: MYSQL, MSSQL

• Tools: Visual Studio, Eclipse, IntellijIdea, Net beans, Resharper, TortoiseSVN,

Emacs, Latex,

SDLC: Waterfall, Agile methodology
Platforms: Linux, Windows, Unix
Unit testing: Nunit, Junit, Spock

EXPERIENCE

Graduate Teaching / Research Assistant, The University of Tennessee, TN

8/2014 – 2017

- Graded assignments and projects, and tutored for undergraduate classes 'Algorithm Analysis and Automata' and 'Software Engineering' during academic year 2014 - 2015
- Developed programs for simulations of mathematical models and plotting graphs using C/C++ and gnuplot for Dr. Sergey Gavrilets in Ecology and Evolutionary Biology Department during 2014 – 2017
- Used cluster computing for simulations and fixed maintenance issues in the cluster

Software Engineer, Deerwalk Services Pvt. Ltd., Nepal

1/2012 - 7/2014

- Developed web applications using objected oriented programming and agile methodology for health care system management in US using ASP.Net, ASP.Net MVC and C#
- Implemented N-tiered application layers; used Entity Framework in data access layer and used web / WCF services in business layer
- Designed and developed database schema and stored procedures in MSSQL
- Developed and maintained US health care system management web application modules using Grails framework

- Worked with RESTful web service in Grails application
- Designed and developed database schema, scripts and stored procedures in MYSQL
- Led developer's team for development and optimization of generic **MYSQL** scripts for importing staged data from multiple clients into company's product's database system